HARRISON MILLER

Los Angeles, CA $_{\circ}$ 9546323386 $_{\circ}$ hmaxmiller@gmail.com

hmaxmiller.com



Enterprise Software Engineer at SpaceX. Full-Stack Developer Specializing in React & React Native. Yale University '17 Graduate. 4 years Software Development.

Summary

Fast learner specializing in mobile application development, technical consulting, UI/UX research, and Agile/SCRUM methodologies. 4 years experience in JavaScript, React, React Native, and C, with desire to earn new languages and tools enthusiastically as needed. Demonstrated ability in acquiring business knowledge and using data-driven approaches to product design and development. Highly social
personality and natural leadership ability. Hungry to take on the challenge of a lifetime. Authorized to work in the U.S. for any employer. Technical Skills
1 ecnnical Skills

Tools & Languages

- JavaScript ES5/ES6/ES7
- React
- React Native
- Redux
- NodeJS
- GraphQL
- Bootstrap
- (
- Design & Development
- Mobile Application Architecture
- Mobile UX Design
- Technical Consulting
- Research Methods
- Sketch
- Waffle.io
- Trello

Work experience

2017 - Present

Enterprise Software Engineer

SpaceX

- Youngest member of Enterprise Information Systems Build Reliability team, whose mission-critical applications work to ensure and enforce quality throughout SpaceX's rocket manufacturing systems.
- Responsible for designing and developing fast, reliable enterprise application to meet growing business demands.
- Gaining technical experience with AngularJS, C#, and API design to supplement existing React and ES6 expertise.
- Implemented and took ownership of a major ERP product feature that is now used throughout SpaceX in production.

2016 - 2017

Technical Consultant, Full-Stack Engineering

Celena

- Led technical assessments and software development for Celena consultancy client projects. Specialty in full-stack JavaScript applications using React, React Native, and NodeJS.
- Facilitated a data-driven approach to prioritize and implement front-end features in the product development cycle for client MVPs.
- Spearheaded the implementation of web and mobile applications based on functional, design, and technical specifications.
- Supervised and managed performance of team of designers, engineers, and contractors focused on optimizing service to client base.

2014 - 2016

Developer & UX Researcher

Various Early-Stage Companies

- Received \$10000 in fellowships to build out MVPs for early stage student ventures, including Venture (collegiate activities-based social networking mobile app), Membra (public speaking anxiety solution), and Celestrix (VR archery training simulator).
- Executed MVP development based on user feedback and market analysis, often with completion in under 4 months. Executed on full product design cycle by defining product requirements, creating user flow diagrams, and producing high-fidelity prototypes.
- Collaborated with an engineering team by leading biweekly development sprints as well as conducting full QA assessments of each release.
- Defined and monitored product usage KPIs to inform subsequent product iterations.

2015 - 2015

E-Commerce Engineering Intern

Faithlife Corporation

- I chose this internship in particular because it provided some unique opportunities to learn about text mining, NLP, and sales engineering.
- Designed and built an internal tool for remote sales quoting, in order to solve problem of painful latency bottlenecks.
- Gained significant experience with microservices architecture, isomorphic JavaScript frameworks, and Express APIs.
- Worked closely with commerce PMs and sales staff to build internal quote-to-cash tool Implemented, tested, and shipped the tool, allowing the commerce team to close sales 60% faster.
- Presented these speedups before a 2000+ audience at the company Demo Day conference in July 2015.

2014 - 2015

Front-End Engineer

Yale University

- Designed, built, and optimized author website for Stephen S. Roach, former Chief Economist & Chairman of Morgan Stanley Asia, to promote new book (Unbalanced: The Codependency of America and China).
- Increased site traffic and conversion KPI's for book purchases with targeted SEO strategies.
- Implemented and maintained search functionality based on timsort & Rabin-Karp string matching for database of 100+ op-ed articles.

Education

2012 - 2017

Bachelor of Arts

Yale University

Joint Psychology with Computer Science program focusing onHuman-Computer Interaction. Read thesis here: https://www.hmaxmiller.com/HumorEvaluationsHCI.pdf

Community Involvement

- Yale Entrepreneurial Institute Venture Creation Program, \$2500 Fellowship
- National Society of Black Engineers Elected Member, Yale University Chapter
- YHack Hackathon Event Organizer (1500+ hackers)
- Research Fellowships \$5000 Miller Lab Fellowship, \$1000 Richter Fellowship, \$1000 Babcock Fellowship